Guide to the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Collection ARS.0056
Archive of Recorded Sound
Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Collection.
1967-1989
ARS.0056
Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.
14 boxes 242 audiocassettes; 38 7" open reel tapes; photographs, transcripts; supplemental print materials; related monographs
Archive of Recorded Sound, Stanford University Libraries, Stanford, California 94305-3076
The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) Collection contains oral history interviews on audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes, transcripts (full and excerpts), photographs, and supplemental materials and related monographs.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biographical/Historical note
WILPF had its roots in the U. S. Women’s Peace party, and was founded in 1915 by 1300 women from neutral and warring nations who met in the Hague, Netherlands to try to negotiate the end of the war, send envoys from their group to nations at war and the U.S., and to urge peaceful resolution and ‘continuous mediation’ to avoid future conflicts. WILPF’s second congress met in Versailles in 1919 where the peace terms were negotiated, and the women’s congress made several long-term resolutions for disarmament, gender equality, and for a world body to negotiate peaceful settlement of conflicts (although WILPF was critical of the League of Nations). President Wilson used many of their proposals in his 14 Point Peace Plan.
Jane Addams, named the first president of WILPF, became the second woman (and the first American woman) to win the Nobel Peace Prize in 1931. Longtime WILPF board member Emily Greene Balch also won the Nobel Peace Prize, in 1946.
The U.S. section of WILPF opposed U.S. participation in WWII (although members supported the troops). In the 1950s, WILPF members rallied against the HUAC hearings. WILPF worked against nuclear testing, and many members also joined the grassroots Women Strike for Peace, a less hierarchical peace-action group. In the 1960s, WILPF was a critical force in the anti-Vietnam War movement. WILPF continues to take a strong stand on issues related to peace and women's equality as a U.N. Non-Governmental Organization (NGO).
The Women's Peace Oral History project was organized by Judith Porter Adams, who began the project in 1979, to celebrate WILPF’s 70th anniversary. The project interviewed ninety older women from local California and other states’ branches. Adams, her students at Stanford and San Jose State, and volunteers conducted the interviews. The project’s goal was to preserve the stories of how the women became committed to peace and justice issues, and what sustained them over their lifetime of activism.”
Scope and Contents
The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Collection consists of 232 audiocassettes housed in 7 boxes and 38 7" open reel tapes housed in 2 boxes. The collection also contains supplemental print and manuscript materials housed in 4 boxes. The oral history interviews that comprise the collection were recorded between roughly 1979 and 1989. Some of the 7" open reel tapes contain recordings of the 1967 WILPF National Conference at Asilomar. The print and manuscript material have varied date ranges. The interviews are the product of the Women's Peace Oral History project, which began in 1979. As the director of the Women's Peace Oral History project, Judith Porter Adams trained student and volunteer interviewers, coordinated and funded the national project with support of the Jane Addams Peace Association and individual donations, and collected and arranged the materials now housed at the Archive of Recorded Sound. The interviewees include ‘rank and file’ as well as prominent members who have held state, national, and international leadership positions in WILPF and Women Strike for Peace (many were active in both). With a few exceptions, older women (over 60) were interviewed because of their years of involvement in peace and justice issues. Those who are still alive in the year this collection was processed by the ARS are still dedicated activists in their late 80’s and 90’s.
Preservation Copies
See also WILPF Oral History Project tapes in Preservation Master Tape Collection, ARS0097.
Digital Collection
All interviews from this collection have been digitized. Many of these are available to stream or download via Stanford's library catalog, Searchworks
Indexing Terms
Women Strike for Peace.; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.
- 1. San Jose Branch., 1983 to 1985
  - 1. Dorothy Aspinwall Interview., 1984-04-19 to 1984-05-23; Dorothy Aspinwall interviewed by Mark Knipper.; Aspinwall, Dorothy; Knipper, Mark
    - Interview, April 19, 1984., 1984-04-19; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 1)
    - Interview, April 19, 1984 and April 27, 1984., 1984-04-19 and 1984-04-27; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 2)
    - Interview, April 27, 1984., 1984-04-27; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 3)
    - Interview, May 4, 1984 and May 7, 1984., 1984-05-04 and 1984-05-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 4)
    - Interview, May 7, 1984., 1984-05-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 5)
    - Interview, May 23, 1984 and April 22, 1985., 1984-05-23 and 1984-05-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 6)
    - Interview, April 22, 1985., 1985-04-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 7)
    - Bio/historical note; Published Letter, April 27, 1984., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 2. Florence R. Bird Interview., 1984-04-25 to 1984-05-02; Bird, Florence R.; Cashion, Nancy
    - Interview, April 25, 1984., 1984-04-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 8)
    - Interview, April 28,1984., 1984-04-28; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 9)
    - Interview, May 2, 1984., 1984-05-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 10)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 3. Nanon (Nan) Bixler Interview., 1984-03-27 and 1984-04-17; Bixler, Nanon (Nan); Coats, Eleana
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript; Obituary; Newspaper clippings., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 4. Marjorie Boehm Interview., 1984; Boehm, Marjorie Moore; Jeffries, Mary
    - Interview One, Spring 1984., 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 11)
    - Interview Two, Spring 1984., 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 12)
    - Interviews Three and Four, Spring 1984., 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 13)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Mary Jeffries' Oral History Report on Interview., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 5. Jeanne Buell Interview., 1984-04-04 to 1984-04-19; Buell, Jeanne; Redman, Christy
    - Interview, April 4, 1984., 1984-04-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 14)
      Transcript
      A transcribed excerpt from this interview can be found in, Adams, Judith Porter. (1991). Peacework: Oral Histories of Women Peace Activists. Boston: Twayne Publishers.
    - Interview, April 7, 1984., 1984-04-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 15)
    - Interview, April 18, 1984., 1984-04-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 16)
    - Interview, April 19, 1984., 1984-04-19; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 17)
    - Bio/historical note; Index., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 6. Alice Cox Interview., 1984-04-03 to 1984-04-10; Arimura, Arlene; Cox, Alice; Perrin, Helen
    - Interview, April 3, 1984., 1984-04-03; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 22)
    - Interview, April 10, 1984., 1984-04-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 23)
    - Interview, April 24, 1984, Part One., 1984-04-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 20)
    - Interview, April 24, 1984, Part Two., 1984-04-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 21)
    - Alice Cox's mother, Helen Perrin, Interview, April 24, 1984, Part One., 1984-04-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 18)
      Restricted
      This item is restricted and is not available to researchers under any condition.
    - Alice Cox's mother, Helen Perrin, Interview, April 24, 1984, Part Two., 1984-04-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 19)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Helen Perrin Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 7. Inez Jackson Interview., 1985-10-22; Adams, Judith Porter; Jackson, Inez
    - Interview, October 22, 1985, Part One., 1985-10-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 24)
    - Interview, October 22, 1985, Part Two., 1985-10-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 25)
    - Biographical notes; Transcript; Newspaper clipping; Benefit Event Program, February 27, 1988; Other papers., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - 8. Lisa Kalvelage Interview., 1985-10-22; Adams, Judith Porter; Kalvelage, Lisa
    - Interview, October 22, 1985, Part One., 1985-10-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 26)
    - Interview, October 22, 1985, Part Two., 1985-10-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 27)
    - Interview, October 22, 1985, Part Three., 1985-10-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 28)
    - Bio/historical note; Newspaper clipping, October 15, 1967., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - 9. Barbara (Barby) Ulmer Interview., 1983-04-06 to 1984-04-27; Nutz, Peggy; Ulmer, Barbara
    - Interview, April 6, 1983., 1983-04-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 32)
    - Interview, April 16, 1984., 1984-04-16; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 31)
    - Interview, April 20, 1984., 1984-04-20; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 30)
    - Interview April 27, 1984., 1984-04-27; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 29)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Student Paper by Peggy Nutz on Barbara Ulmer and Our Developing World, May 8, 1984; Our Developing World website information., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - 10. Gertrude Welch Interview., 1984-04-12 to 1984-05-10; Langager, Peggy J.; Welch, Gertrude
    - Interview, April 12, 1984., 1984-04-12; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 33)
    - Interview, April 18, 1984., 1984-04-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 34)
    - Interview, May 10, 1984., 1984-05-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 1, Cassette 35)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Newspaper clipping, June 3, 2005; Newspaper clipping, October 14, 2001; Reflections on the life of Gertrude Welch, by Richard Hobbs., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
- 2. San Francisco and East Bay Branches., 1979 to 1989
  - 1. Leona Wolff (Leona M. Bayer, M.D.) Interview., 1980-12-01 to 1985-09-18; Adams, Judith Porter; Bayer, Leona M. (Leona Mayer), 1903; Gusterson, Hugh; Rosenlicht, Carla
    Restricted material
    All materials, both audio and text, from this interview has been restricted and is not therefore not available for research.
    - Interview, December 1, 1980., 1980-12-01; 1 audiocassette; Rosenlicht, Carla (Audio 2, Cassette 36)
    - Interview, December 15, 1980., 1980-12-15; 1 audiocassette; Rosenlicht, Carla (Audio 2, Cassette 37)
    - Interview, January 19, 1981., 1981-01-19; 1 audiocassette; Rosenlicht, Carla (Audio 2, Cassette 38)
    - Interview, March 1, 1981., 1981-03-01; 1 audiocassette; Rosenlicht, Carla (Audio 2, Cassette 39)
    - Interview, September 18, 1985, Part One., 1985-09-18; 1 audiocassette; Gusterson, Hugh (Audio 2, Cassette 40)
    - Interview, September 18, 1985, Part Two., 1985-09-18; 1 audiocassette; Gusterson, Hugh (Audio 2, Cassette 41)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript; WILPF - The Long View, Looking Back and Looking Foward, May 10, 1986; Unpublished Note on Erik Erikson., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - 2. Anna Burke Interview., 1985-12-17; Burke, Anna; Gardner, Maxine
    - Interview, December 17, 1985., 1985-12-17; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 42)
  - 3. Patricia Cody Interview., 1986-02-25; Cody, Patricia; Hamburg, Alice
    - Interview, February 25, 1986, Part One., 1986-02-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 43)
    - Interview, February 25, 1986, Part Two., 1986-02-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 44)
    - Letter to Alice Hamburg regarding Fred Cody, April 14, 1986; Obituary, 2010; Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 4. Rose Dellamonica Interview., 1985-09-10; Adams, Judith Porter; Dellamonica, Rose
    - Interview, September 10, 1985, Part One., 1985-09-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 45)
    - Interview, September 10, 1985, Part Two., 1985-09-10; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 46)
    - Handwritten essay, undated; Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 5. Madeline Duckles Interview., 1985-11-22; Adams, Judith Porter; Duckles, Madeline
    - Interview, November 22, 1985, Part One., 1985-11-22; 1 audiocassette 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 47)
    - Interview, November 22, 1985, Part Two., 1985-11-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 48)
    - Transcript; Bio/historical note; Monthly newsletter of MLK Jr Peacemobile Project, April-May 1986; Obituary; Other papers., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 6. Clara Gilbert Interview., 1985-11-15 to 1986-01-14; Gilbert, Clara; Havirack, June
    - Interview, November 15, 1985 and January 14, 1986., 1985-11-15 to 1986-01-14; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 49)
  - 7. Hazel Grossman Interview., 1986-01-26; Grossman, Hazel; Gusterson, Hugh
    - Interview, January 26, 1986, Part One., 1986-01-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 50)
    - Interview, January, 26, 1986, Part Two., 1986-01-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 51)
    - Interview, January 26, 1986, Part Three., 1986-01-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 52)
    - Interview, January 26, 1986, Part Four., 1986-01-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 53)
    - Letter to Nguyen Kim Xuan, December 20, 1984; Cartoon of "personalities at the California Labor School; Obituary for the Hazel Grossman's husband, Aubrey Grossman., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 8. Alice Hamburg Interview., 1979-11-13 to 1986-05-07; Adams, Judith Porter; Hamburg, Alice; Wells, Tom, 1955 -
    - Interview, November 13, 1979., 1979-11-13; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 54)
    - Interview, May 7, 1986., 1986-05-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 55)
    - Other Papers; Newpaper clipping; Letters; Transcript of Tom Wells Interview., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 9. Erna Harris Interview., 1985-11-22; Adams, Judith Porter; Harris, Erna
    - Interview, November 22, 1985, Part One., 1985-11-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 56)
    - Interview, November 22, 1985, Part Two., 1985-11-22; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 57)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Funeral Service Program and Papers, March 9, 1995., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 10. Margaret Calder Hayes Interview., 1985-10-04; Adams, Judith Porter; Hayes, Margaret Calder
    - Interview, October 4, 1985, Part One., 1985-10-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 58)
    - Interview, October 4, 1985, Part Two., 1985-10-04; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 59)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript; Obituary; Magazine clipping; Obituary for Hayes son, Kenneth Hayes., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 21a)
  - 11. Frances W. Herring Interview., 1985; Herring, Frances W.; West, Jane; Wilson, Beth
    - Interview, May 2, 1985., 1985-05-02; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 60)
    - Interview, Spring 1985, Part One., 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 61)
    - Interview, Spring 1985, Part Two., 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 62)
    - Transcript; Bio/historical note; Index; Letter to Judy Adams, February 6, 1985; Women Strike for Peace pamphlet; The Financial Implications of Divestment by Frances Herring; Statement on the Nuclear Safeguards Initiative, December 9, 1975; Report from trip to Russia, July 10, 1960; Economic and Social Impact of Disarmament by Frances Herring, July 1962; Picture of Herring with Alice Richards., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 12. Mary Addams Hulbert Interview., 1985-08-07; Adams, Judith Porter; Hulbert, Mary Addams
    - Interview, August 7, 1985, Part One., 1985-08-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 63)
    - Interview, August 7, 1985, Part Two., 1985-08-07; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 64)
    - Transcript; Copy of booklet entitled Cedarville's Jane Adams, by Ronald H. Beam, copyright 1966; Correspondence to Hulbert from editor of Jane Addams Papers, Mary Lynn McCree Bryan., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 13. Rose Marciano Lucey Interview., 1989-01-14; Adams, Judith Porter; Lucey, Rose Marciano
    - Interview, January 14, 1989, Part One., 1989-01-14; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 65)
    - Interview, January 14, 1989, Part Two., 1989-01-14; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 66)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript; 1989 article in National Catholic Reporter., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - 14. Enola Maxwell Interview., 1985-09-23; Adams, Judith Porter; Maxwell, Enola
    - Interview, September 23, 1985., 1985-09-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 67)
    - Interview, September 23, 1985., 1985-09-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 68)
    - Newspaper clipping, November 30, 1977; Newpaper clippings, July, 1983; Newspaper clipping, August 15, 1983. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - 15. Frances Millhouser Interview., 1986-04-21; Gardner, Maxine; Millhouser, Frances
    - Interview, April 21, 1986., 1986-04-21; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 69)
    - Index., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 16. Marion Paxton Interview., 1985-09-24; Adams, Judith Porter; Paxton, Marion
    - Interview, September 24, 1985., 1985-09-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 70)
    - Interview, September 24, 1985., 1985-09-24; 1 audiocassette (Audio 2, Cassette 71)
    - Bio/historical note., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 17. Vicky Plaisted Interview., 1986-06-02; Hamburg, Alice; Plaisted, Vicky
    - Transcript., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 18. Margaret Rowell Interview., 1985-11-25; Adams, Judith Porter; Rowell, Margaret
    - Interview, November 25, 1985, Part One., 1985-11-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 72)
    - Interview, November 25, 1985, Part Two., 1985-11-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 73)
    - Obituaries; Article entitled Margaret Rowell: Cello Educator., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 19. Betty Segal Interview., 1985-10-26; Hamburg, Alice; Segal, Betty
    - Interview, October 26, 1985., 1985-10-26; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 74)
    - Transcript; Obituary; Article from People Magazine., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 20. Norma Stauffer Interview., 1985-11-25; Adams, Judith Porter; Stauffer, Norma
    - Interview, November 25, 1985, Part One., 1985-11-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 75)
    - Interview, November 25, 1985, Part Two., 1985-11-25; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 76)
    - Bio/historical note., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 21. Ann Stenzel Interview., 1985-11-06; 3; Adams, Judith Porter; Stenzel, Ann
    - Interview, November 6, 1985, Part One., 1985-11-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 77)
    - Interview, November 6, 1985, Part Two., 1985-11-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 78)
    - Interview, November 6, 1985, Part Three., 1985-11-06; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 79)
    - Newsletter, National Association of Social Workers, "Social Work and Human Survival in the Nuclear Age: A Call for Action," September-October 1983. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 22. Augusta Trumpler Interview., 1985-12-16 and 1985-12-19; Hamburg, Alice; Trumpler, Augusta
    - Interview, December 16, 1985., 1986-12-16; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 80)
    - Interview, December 19, 1985., 1985-12-19; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 81)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Transcript; Newspaper clippings and photos., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 23. Leonore Veltfort Interview., 1985-10-31; Adams, Judith Porter; Veltfort, Leonore
    - Interview, October 31, 1985, Part One., 1985-10-31; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 82)
    - Interview, October 31, 1985, Part Two., 1985-10-31; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 83)
  - 24. Helma Waldeck Interview., 1985-09-18 and 1985-09-30; Adams, Judith Porter; Waldeck, Helma
    - Interview, September 18, 1985., 1985-09-18; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 84)
    - Interview, September 30, 1985, Part One., 1985-09-30; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 85)
    - Interview, September 30, 1985, Part Two., 1985-09-30; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 86)
    - Bio/historical note; Other papers., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 55)
- 3. Palo Alto Branch., 1979 -1986
  - 1. Lygia Callejo Interview., 1979-08-01 and 01-20-1981; Adams, Judith Porter; Callejo, Lygia
    - Interview, August 1, 1979 and Interview, January 20, 1981, Part One., 1979-08-01 to 1981-01-20; 1 audiocassette 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 87)
    - Interview, August 1, 1979, copy., 1979-08-01; 1 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 8, Reel 238)
    - Interview, January 20, 1981, Part Two., 1981-01-20; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 88)
    - Interview, January 20, 1981, copy., 1981-01-20; 1 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 8, Reel 239)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Funeral service program; Obituary, 1989., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 2. Isobel Cerney Interview., 1983-12-5 to 1984-9-28; Cerney, Isobel M.; Halper, Leah; Kessler, Steven
    - Interview, December 5, 1983, Part One., 1983-12-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 89)
    - Interview, December 5, 1983, Part Two., 1983-12-05; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 90)
    - Interview, January 11, 1984, Part One., 1984-01-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 91)
    - Interview, January 11, 1984, Part Two., 1984-01-11; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 92)
    - Interview, January 31, 1984., 1984-01-31; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 93)
    - Interview, February 9, 1984., 1984-02-09; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 94)
    - Interview, Spring 1984., 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 95)
    - Interview, September 28, 1984., 1984-09-28; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 96)
    - Bio/historical note; Transcript; Text of the HUAC Hearing in San Diego, July 5 and 6, 1955; Guide to the Edwin H. Cerney Papers, Tamiment Library/Wagner Archives; Index; Newspaper clippings; Letters; Other Papers., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Selected Poems., 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 7.1)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 3. Beth Coats Interview., 1980-02-21; Coats, Beth; Smith, Stephanie
    - Interview, February 21, 1980., 1980-02-21; 1 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 8, Reel 239)
    - Bio/historical note; Index; Obituary., 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Photographs., 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 4. Elizabeth Drake Interview., 1982-11-09 to 1982-11-23; Drake, Elizabeth; Madrid, Rosanna
    - Interview, November 9, 1982., 1982-11-09; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 97)
    - Interviews, November 9, 1982 and November 16, 1982, copy., 1982-11-09 to 1982-11-16; 1 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 8, Reel 252)
    - Interview, November 16, 1982., 1982-11-16; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 98)
    - Interview, November 23, 1982, Part One., 1982-11-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 99)
    - Interview, November 23, 1982, Part Two., 1982-11-23; 1 audiocassette (Audio 3, Cassette 100)
    - Interview, November 23, 1982, copy., 1982-11-23; 1 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 8, Reel 253)